CHAN Ka Lung, Oscar 陳嘉隆 Frontend Developer

oscarchankalung.github.io github.com/oscarchankalung linkedin.com/in/oscarchankalung in oscarchankalung@gmail.com

A self-driven programmer embarking upon a career in software development. Experienced in building the frontend of commercial web and mobile apps. Always strive to balance time, product quality and maintainability. Motivated to position myself within an environment that has an open and established set of values that are adhered to. Determined to be continually challenged both personally and technically.

Skills

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript
- React, Angular, Redux, Sass, Bootstrap, jQuery
- Python, SQL, Git, MacOS Command Line
- Adobe Photoshop, XD, Figma

Work Experience

Frontend Developer, AppicIDEA IT Solutions, Hong Kong

04/2021 - 12/2021

Technologies: Typescript, React Native, Angular, Firebase, Figma, Bitbucket

- Developed the frontend of 3 React Native mobile apps (wine inventory management, online shopping and mental health promotion)
- Developed the frontend of 2 Angular web apps (elderly service and library system)
- Adopt agile development using Atlassian technology

Technical Business Analyst, Macquarie, Hong Kong

10/2018 - 03/2020

Technologies: Alteryx, API, Confluence, MongoDB

- Incorporated new data processing tools to enable automation within the middle office
- Automated over 30 reconciliations/reports, annually saving 40 hours per workflow
- Migrated over 20 trade/position reconciliations from a vendor to the internal system, which improved the user experience and avoided the cost of a premium upgrade
- Developed an email-based daily reconciliations break monitoring tool, which made error discovery and solving faster
- Created user guides and trained 8 trade supports to use Alteryx, who initiated over 20 automation tasks

Community Manager, Coderbunker, Shanghai

12/2017 - 06/2018

Technologies: G Suite (Google Workspace), WeChat Official Account, Strikingly

- Built an international community for software developers to further develop their skills and create opportunities for collaboration with customers
- Delivered presentations and recruited people as freelancers, co-workers or co-learners
- Organized and facilitated co-learning workshops and tech events for 30-100 participants
- Managed the official website and social media accounts for community branding
- Maintained and improved databases using Google Spreadsheet and SQL

Education

Java Development Training Programme, FDM Hong Kong Academy

08/2018 - 10/2018

Trained in the following modules

- Object Oriented Development (Java)
- Database Access in Java (JDBC, JPA/Hibernate)
- Web Development in Java (Servlet, JSPs)
- Spring Framework

Computer Software Engineering, Piscine Program, 42 Silicon Valley, Fremont, California 06/2018 - 07/2018

Survived the admission process of the 42 program, an innovative programming school with a peer-to-peer and project-based learning environment. Zero tuition. Zero teachers. Zero classes.

- Completed an intensive 28 day coding challenge covering the basic of C, Linux, and Git
- Worked in teams to write programs, like sudoku solver and expression evaluator

BSc., Applied Biology (First Class Hons, GPA 3.54), City University of Hong Kong 09/2013 - 07/2017

Awards

• FDM Consultant of the Month Award, APAC Winner, 2019

Interests and Activities

- Reading
- Cooking
- Mindfulness
- Feminism
- Decentralized Technology